PJ FANCHER

Web Developer

PJ Fancher

peejfancher@gmail.com 352-262-5915 pjfancher.com github.com/peejfancher

Overview

I am a Web Developer with 14 years experience. I began writing small web applications with Perl, PHP in 1998. I have well rounded experience with all aspects of Web Development from design (CSS, HTML) to Client-Side Scripting (Javascript, JQuery, AJAX) to Server-Side Scripting (PHP, Python) to Database configuration, design & administration (MySQL) and Web Server configuration. For the past year I have been working heavily with Drupal

Tech Skills

PHP Drupal 7 **MVC** Architecture **SEO** Javascript **JQuery** Wordpress 3.x Database Design Python MySQL HTML5 CakePHP AJAX Database Administration Apache

CSS3 Git Adobe Photoshop LAMP Development Software Training

Employment

Web/Database Administrator No Idea Records

January 2003 - Present | Gainesville, FL

Responsible for all web related duties and development. Originally wrote entire shopping cart and CMS using PHP in 2005. Ungraded site to Drupal 7 in 2012. In charge of managing software and database that handles over 10k orders per year. More details below.

Web/Database Administrator & Registration Team Leader

The Fest

May 2002 - Present | Gainesville, FL

Responsible for designing and implementing online ticket sales for this event for the past 10 years. Last implementation handled a quarter-million dollars in sales in just under 6 hours. Also responsible for designing registration software to get all 5,000+ ticket holders checked into the event weekend of. Day of event registration Team Leader. More details below.

Web/Database Administrator & Sole Proprietor

Downloadmyvinyl.com

July 2008 - Present | Gainesville, FL

Web application that allows paying record labels to generate unique download codes to insert inside their vinyl records. Hosts over 60 record labels from around the world. Sole programmer, manager, customer service rep and accountant.

Freelance Web Developer

October 2010 - Present | Gainesville, FL

Various freelance web development jobs. Details below.

Projects



Razorcake Fanzine & Distro

Los Angeles, CA http://www.razorcake.org

Online store / News Archive, RAZORCAKE is the first and only official non-profit DIY punk rock fanzine in America primarily dedicated to supporting independent music culture. Site built using Drupal 7. Imported over 25,000 nodes from old PHP-Nuke DB into current site using custom PHP scripts and Drupal API. (In final stages of production. New site not yet live.)



No Idea Records & Distro

Gainesville, FL

http://www.noidearecords.com

Online store. No Idea Records is an independent label and distribution company from Gainesville FL. No Idea started as a fanzine in 1985, and released their first 7" in 1988. Site built using Drupal 7. Imported over 5,000 products from old custom CMS into current site using custom PHP scripts and Drupal API.



Total Treble

St. Augustine / Gainesville, FL http://www.totaltreble.com

Online store for Total Treble Music, record label started by the band Against Me! in 2011. (In final stages of production. New site not yet live.)



The FEST Tickets

Gainesville, FL

http://www.thefestfl.com/tickets

Online tickets sales and registration. The Fest is annual music festival that takes place in downtown Gainesville, FL. October 2012 marks its 11th year.



Lead Us Down

Gainesville, FL

http://www.leadusdown.com/

Online Gainesville Music Magazine. News, Articles, Record Reviews and Live Shows Reviews from Gainesville, FL. Completed July 2011.



Re-Elect Sheriff Sadie Darnell

Gainesville, FL

http://www.reelectsheriffdarnell.com

Website for the re-election campaign of Alachua County Sheriff Sadie Darnell. Completed July 2011.



The Floridian

St. Augustine, FL

http://www.thefloridianstaug.com

Website for The Floridian Restaurant in St. Augustine FL. Completed Oct. 2010



Lynnae Hottinger Foundation for Ovarian Cancer Research

Jacksonville, FL

http://www.lynnae.org/

Website for Lynnae Hottinger Foundation for Ovarian Cancer Research. Completed August 2011



Jen & PJ get married

Gainesville, FL

http://www.jenandpjgetmarried.com/

Website for the wedding of Jennifer Davis & PJ Fancher. Completed February 2012



Catharsis Skateboards

Gainesville, FL

http://www.catharsisskateboards.com/

Online Store for Catharsis Skateboard Company. Completed September 2011

Education

A.S., Computer Information Technology & Programming

Santa Fe Community College Gainesville, FL | December 1999 3.8 GPA